Finding Aid for Anonymous Association of Suburban People officer’s papers, 1973-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Anonymous Association of Suburban People officer’s papers 1973-2004, 1976-1985
Anonymous officer of the Association of Suburban People.
1 oversize folders
1 linear feet
2013071 Aa 2 UAl
The collection was created and collected by an officer of the Association of Suburban People who wishes to remain anonymous. It contains legal papers, correspondence, and other official records of the Association of Suburban People, but concentrates on the organization's social activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated, anonymously, in 2013 (donor 9784 ).
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The collection was created and collected by an officer of the Association of Suburban People who wishes to remain anonymous. The Association of Suburban People (ASP) was founded in 1976 as a social and political organization for Metropolitan Detroit gays and lesbians (for most of its history it was primarily a gay male organization). As the name indicates, the ASP reflected the population shift in the Detroit area from the city to the suburbs. By the 1980s the ASP had become the largest LGBT organization in Michigan, and in 1985 it changed its name to South Eastern Michigan Gay and Lesbian Association (SEMGLA) to more accurately describe its mission.
The anonymous creator of this collection was particularly active in the ASP's earlier years, serving as Vice President and chairperson of the Membership Committee (1977-79), Information Officer and chair of the ASP-PAC (1979-80), and Newsletter Editor (1981-82). He remained a member throughout ASP's history.
The collection contains legal papers, correspondence, and other official records of the Association of Suburban People, but concentrates on the organization's social activities. Photographs, flyers, and posters from Hottest Hairy or Hairless Chest Contests, Halloween Contests, and Club Nites are included, events held at the Interchange, the Outlaw, the R & R Saloon, and other Detroit area gay bars.
The collection also includes a collection of matchbooks and matchboxes from gay bars, restaurants, baths, and other businesses in Detroit and surrounding areas, elsewhere in Michigan and Ontario, and to a lesser extent nationwide. A collection of buttons is also included, mainly Detroit gay-related but some from national organizations.
This collection was processed by Douglas M. Haller, ASP Information Officer, 1980-1981. An item listing of the collection with extensive explanatory notes by the processor is appended to this finding aid in the "Additonal Descriptive Data" section.
Subjects:
Association of Suburban People.; Gay liberation movement--Michigan.; Gay men--Michigan.; Gay rights--Michigan.; Gays--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Association of Suburban People.; Contests--Michigan.; Female impersonators--Michigan.; Gay bars--Michigan.; Gay men--Michigan.; Gay rights--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Buttons (information artifacts); Matchbooks.; Matchboxes.; Photographs.
- Papers
  - ASP Records passed from Thomas V. Zeimis (Records Keeper) to Jim Childers circa 1976-1980 (Box 1)
    [Folder 1]
  - ASP Records Jim Childers Copies circa 1979-1984, 1993 (Box 1)
    [Folder 2]
  - Oversize: Posters and Calendar (Folder UAl)
  - Framed Award "Presented To JIMMY CHILDERS In Grateful Recognition Of His Unceasing Efforts To Glorify The American Male And The Association Of Suburban People" (Box 1)
    [folder 3]
  - Newsletter Masters (Original Typescripts/Pastiches) August 1980-February 1981 (Box 1)
    [Folder 4]
  - Newsletter Enclosures or Handouts-Miscellaneous undated (Box 1)
    [Folder 5]
  - Newsletter Enclosures circa July-October, 1982 (Box 1)
    [Folder 6]
- ASP 'Club Nites' at Detroit Bars (Interchange, Outlaw, R & R, CCW), 1980-84
  - Hottest Hairy/Hairless Chest Contests at The Interchange 1501 Holden, Detroit (1980-1984)
    - Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#I), Jul 3 1980
      - Papers (Box 1)
        [Folder 7]
      - Photographs (Box 1)
        [Folder 8]
    - Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#II), Jul 10, 1981/Contestant Brunch, Jul 12 1981
      - Papers (Box 1)
        [Folder 9]
      - Photographs (Box 1)
        [Folder 10]
    - Hottest Hairless Chest Contest (#I) September, 1981 (Box 1)
      [Folder 11]
    - Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#III), Jul 3 1982
      - Papers (Box 1)
        [Folder 12]
      - Photographs (Box 1)
        [Folder 13]
    - Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#IV), Jul 2 1983
      - Papers (Box 1)
        [Folder 14]
      - Photographs (Box 1)
        [Folder 15]
    - Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#V, sic #VI), Jun 30 1984
      - Papers (Box 1)
        [Folder 16]
      - Photographs (Box 1)
        [Folder 17]
  - Halloween Contests at The Interchange 1501 Holden, Detroit, 1980-1982
    - Halloween Night Contest, Oct 31 1980 (Box 1)
      [Folder 18]
    - Halloween Night Contest, Oct 31 1981
      - Papers (Box 1)
        [Folder 19]
      - Photographs (Box 1)
        [Folder 20]
    - Halloween Contest, Oct 30 1982 (date of contest) (Box 1)
      [Folder 21]
  - Club Nites at the Outlaw 1028 W. Seven Mile Rd., Detroit, 1981-1982
    - Papers (Box 1)
      [Folder 22]
    - Photographs December 5, 1981 (Box 1)
      [Folder 23]
  - Club Nites at the R & R Saloon 6918 Michigan Ave., Detroit, 1982
    - Papers (Box 1)
      [Folder 24]
    - Photographs February 27, 1982 (Box 1)
      [Folder 25]
  - Bar Nite at C.C.W. (Country Western Saloon), 16103 W. Warren, Detroit, Jun 20 1980 and Miscellaneous Materials Related to Club Nites, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    [Folder 26]
- Photographs
  - Incoming/Outgoing Executive Boards 1982 Newsletter Committee, 1981-82 (Box 1)
    [Folder 27]
  - Miscellaneous Photos, Woodbridge Neighborhood, Detroit circa 1980s (Box 1)
    [Folder 28]
  - Sixth Annual Raunchy Western Review, Oct 5 1985
    - Photograph Album (Box 1)
      [Folder 29]
    - Negatives (Box 1)
      [Folder 30]
- Matchbooks and Matchboxes
  - Detroit, Other Michigan, Windsor Gay Bars, Restaurants, Baths (Box 1)
    [Folder 31]
  - Other American and Canadian Gay Bars, Restaurants, Businesses (Box 1)
    [Folder 32]
- Gay/ Lesbian Buttons
  - General 1980-1999 (Box 1)
    [Folder 33]
  - Detroit and Michigan 1976-1993 (Box 1)
    [Folder 34]
Inventory and Descriptive Notes Prepared by the Donor
Series I ASP Records ca. 1976-1980 passed from Thomas V. Zeimis (Records Keeper) to Jim Childers [Folder 1]
Including: Articles of Incorporation (May 7, 1976) & original Charter (1976)
correspondence from Brother Bo Taylor (Herbert Taylor), Gay West Wayne Men/ ASP (Feb-Jul, 1976)
Detroit News notice of ASP establishment (May 18, 1976)
ASP at Dignity Detroit Banquet (May 8, 1976)
Birmingham/Bloomfield Observer & Eccentric article on ASP (Jun 24, 1976)
ASP Disco Dance at Plymouth Hilton Inn (Jun 26, 1976)
ASP 'Statue of Liberty' logo (Oct 2, 1976)
ASP election endorsements in Metro Gay News (Oct 12,1976 for Nov election)
flyer stating ASP formation date as Nov, 1975 & purposes as both political & social (1977)
ASP letters re: Anita Bryant & Dave Kopay (1977)
ASP Disco Party in Dearborn Heights (1977)
ASP- sponsored events in Dearborn Heights during Gay Pride Week (Jun, 1977)
ASP letters in support of the Equal Rights Amendment (1977-78)
ASP letters to Detroit Board of Police Commissioners & Common Council re: illegal arrests of (as many as 100) homosexuals in the 16th Precinct (1977)
ASP dance/speaker at Bookie's Club 870, Detroit during Gay Pride Week (1978)
Bob-Lo Standards of Conduct (for same-sex visitors) during Gay Pride Week (1977, 78 or 79)
ASP Hayride (1978?)
ASP Phone Chain (1979)
ASP's 'relatively new' Bar Night at the Escape, Detroit (1979)
ASP-sponsored films & disco party during Gay Pride (1979)
ASP planned camping trip to Summit Lodge Resort, Ohio (1979)
Marketing Plan for ASP (1979-80)
ASP-sponsored trip to Toronto (no date)
ASP Revised Charter due to IRS regulations & MI state law (no date).
Series II ASP Records ca. 1979-1984, 1993 Jim Childers Copies [Folder 2]
Including: ASP Amended Charter providing that the Newsletter Editor is an Officer appointed by the Executive Board etc. (Feb 25, 1979), with cover letter & notice of election (ca. Apr 22, 1979)
letter from the ASP Executive Board designating Margareth [Miller] of Ann Arbor as its second Honorary Member (May 6, 1979)
ASP Secretary Frank Martin's minutes of the brainstorming session held at Dan Sivil's on Jan 27, 1980, Phil Green as facilitator (cover note Jan 31, 1980)
ASP 1982-83 General Election Ballot (P- Tim Kieselhorst, VP- Wes Rogalski, T- George Neely, S- Frank Martin, I O- write-in only)
Letter from Dan Sivil to Jim Childers re: expenses for Hottest Hairy Chest Contest at the Interchange bar (ca. 1980-84) & METRA (Magazine) Picnic, etc.
Counselor helped others in pain (Detroit Free Press, Dec 9, 1993), obituary of ASP member James Pomann (b. James Pomianek, Dearborn, MI; d. Nov 28, 1993, 45 years old, West Palm Beach, FL).
Series III Oversize: Posters (6 items), Calendar (1 item) [Outsize folder UAl]
1) Mr. Hairy Chest Presented by the Association of Suburban People/ Interchange Bar; Jun 30, 1984 (1501 Holden, Detroit); 17 3/4" l x 11" w
2) Sit on It! Free VD Tests! Metro Detroit Gay VD Council, Highland Park/ Akron Health Club, Detroit; 17" l x 11" w
3) Moonlight Cruise on the Bob-Lo Boat (Detroit); Jun 11, 1982; signed Sigmann; 18" l x 23 3/4" w
4) Women's Dance/ Dykes' Dance Presented by Gay Awareness Women's Kolective, Ann Arbor; Dec 15, 1973; 17" l x 11" w
5) San Francisco After Dan White Verdict 1979; Photo Peter Griesinger, Griesinger Films, Rock Cave, WV c. 1979; signed "#274 Peter Root/f (?) Griesinger" In original mailing tube postmarked Feb 15, 1980; 22" l x 28" w
6) The Barn & The Stables The Hangout in Downtown Toronto- July 2004 8 1/2" l x 11" w From a color photograph showing a painted mural on the exterior wall of the bar with two cowboys holding hands, as an advertisement for Molson Canadian beer.
7) Magnum, p.i. 1985 Calendar; Landmark Calendars, Sausalito, CA c. 1984, c. 1983 Universal City Studios, Inc. (Thomas W. Selleck b. Jan 29, 1945 Detroit)
8) Framed Award "Presented To JIMMY CHILDERS In Grateful Recognition Of His Unceasing Efforts To Glorify The American Male And The Association Of Suburban People," with miniature jock strap affixed to glass (inside label: 'The' DUKE, small, made in USA).
Series IV Newsletter Masters (Original Typescripts/Pastiches) 4 items [Folder 4]
Newsletter masters for Aug, 1980; Nov, 1980; Dec, 1980 and Feb, 1981 (created during or prior to the Newsletter Editorship(s) of Jim Childers).
Series V Newsletter Enclosures or Handouts- Miscellaneous (undated) [Folder 5]
1) Flyer master 'Wanna' Spend the Night?? How About the Weekend???' ASP Weekend in Saugatuck, MI, Jun 27 (no year), call Al Redner for details.
2) Flyer master 'The First Annual A.S.P. Benefit Tupperware Party,' Sun, Mar 11 (no year) at the home of Greg Butler, Birmingham, MI, call Greg or Jim; '50' annotation on verso.
3) Flyer master, 'N.G.T.F. (National Gay Task Force) Benefit Dinner,' Jan 20 (no year), four-course home-cooked meal as benefit for NGTF which is experiencing financial difficulties; '50 copies' annotation on verso.
4) Printed Petition to all U.S. Congressional Representatives & President Ronald Reagan as Self-Mailer, 'Stop The Family Protection Act!! Senate Bill S1378 & House Bill HR3955,' prepared by National Gay Task Force, New York, ca. 1981.
Series VI Newsletter Enclosures (ca. Jul--Oct, 1982) [Folder 6]
"Late Evidence on Contagious Causes [of AID/ AIDS] (supplement)" by Lawrence Mass, M.D.; post Jul 16, 1982; 'insert one in each newsletter' handwritten at top.
Sincere Staging Helps 'Falsettos' by Jay Carr; The Detroit News, Sep 20, 1982
ASP Calendar; Oct, 1982 Including notices of 'March of the Falsettos' benefit performance at the Attic Theatre, Detroit and Whitman Brooks Conference 'Developing a Positive Gay Identity' at Marygrove College, Detroit.
Flyer 'March of the Falsettos' by William Finn; ASP/ MOHR benefit performance at the Attic Theater, Detroit; Oct 6, 1982
Brochure "Developing a Positive Gay-Lesbian Identity;" ASP/ Whitman Brooks Foundation of Los Angeles; Oct 17, 1982; Marygrove College, Detroit
Series VII ASP 'Club Nites' at Detroit Bars (Interchange, Outlaw, R & R, CCW) 1980-84 [Folders 7-26]
Posters, original artwork for flyers, Polaroid photographs of contestants, card announcements as publicity, completed release forms from contestants, and lists of winners selected by bar patrons for ASP 'club nites' held at Detroit bars (usually catering to Gay leather/levi and Country-Western clientele) as promotions for ASP membership recruitment, entertainment for members, and promotions of Gay bars as community businesses/ meeting spaces.
Hottest Hairy/ Hairless Chest Contests at The Interchange, 1501 Holden, Detroit (1980-1984)
1) Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#I) Jul 3, 1980 [Folders 7-8]
Flyer with original pen-and-ink drawing, unsigned; card announcement for contest as publicity (business card size); 19 Polaroid color photographs of 23 numbered contestants (2 of contestant #8). The photograph for contestant #6 (straw cowboy hat, chain harness & black leather wrist band) shows the ASP 'Hottest Hairy Chest Contest' flyer for Jul 3, 1980 mounted on the wall behind the contestant, which is how this group of photographs was identified as such.
2) Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#II) Jul 10, 1981/ Contestant Brunch Jul 12, 1981 [Folders 9-10]
24 Polaroid color photographs of 20 contestants and 5 individuals (3 unnumbered contestants, 2 others fully clothed, one of whom is ASP member/officer Doug Smart (straw cowboy hat, blue shirt) and the other wearing an ASP T-shirt); original poster/registration application requesting contact information and photograph; 21 completed applications from contestants (5 Detroit, 3 Dearborn, 2 Plymouth, 2 Southgate, and 1 each from Redford, Taylor, Rochester, Livonia, Dearborn Heights, Pontiac, Grand Rapids, Flint, and Toledo, OH; 2 pp. handwritten listing of contestants, number of votes received, & top three winners (Flint, Dearborn, Dearborn); and card announcement for contest as publicity (slightly larger than a business card).
3) Hottest Hairless Chest Contest (#I) September, 1981 [Folder 11]
Eight Polaroid color photographs of 8 contestants; and handwritten listing of contestants, number of votes received (including ASP member/ officer Doug Dennis).
4) Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#III) Jul 3, 1982 [Folders 12-13]
18 Polaroid color photographs of 20 contestants; three b/w snapshots showing the winner, 3rd place winner (#3 on belt) and ASP officer Jim Childers; 2 pp. handwritten listing of contestants, number of votes received, & top three winners; 20 completed applications from contestants requesting contact information and photograph (6 Detroit, 3 Ann Arbor, 2 Flint, and 1 each from Redford, Mt. Clemens, East Lansing, Utica, Centerline, Sterling Heights, Lansing, Plymouth, and Toronto, Ont; 20 completed release forms from contestants allowing ASP & their agents to use their 'picture and first name with last initial' or 'last name' and asking if they would like to be placed on the ASP mailing list; three unmarked poster/registration applications with photograph by Rick Krause.
5) Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#IV) Jul 2, 1983 [Folders 14-15]
13 Polaroid color photographs of 11 contestants (3 of contestant #3, 2 of contestant #9); handwritten listing of 11 contestants, number of votes received, & top three winners; 12 completed applications and releases from contestants (4 Detroit, and 1 each from Farmington Hills, Utica, Waterford, Southgate, Westland, Toledo, OH and Windsor, Ont); three unmarked poster/registration applications with photograph by Rick Krause.
6) Hottest Hairy Chest Contest (#V, sic #VI) Jun 30, 1984 [Folders 16-17]
Note: This is the fifth Hairy Chest Contest and the sixth if the Hairless Chest Contest in 1981 is included.
12 Polaroid color photographs of 13 contestants (one cancelled); handwritten listing of 13 contestants (1 cancellation), number of votes received, & top three winners; 12 completed applications and releases from contestants (4 Detroit, and 1 each from Royal Oak, Warren, Dearborn Heights, Westland, Farmington Hills, Garden City, Kitchener, Ont and Toronto, Ont.); three unmarked poster/registration applications with photograph by Rick Krause.
Halloween Contests at The Interchange, 1501 Holden, Detroit (1980-1982)
Note: Materials in this sub-series were intermingled within the envelopes that contained them. The best effort has been made to separate them as follows:
1) Halloween Night Contest (Oct 31, 1980) [Folder 18]
Flyer, "The Male Animal as Fantasy!" (based on original artwork).
2) Halloween Night Contest (Oct 31, 1981) [Folders 19-20]
Flyer master, original pen-and-ink drawing, "Hottest Male Fantasy,"signed Re (ASP member/ officer Robert Re); 14 Polaroid color photographs of 10 contestants and four group shots of the top three winners (#9, #5 & #3) & other contestants; 10 completed releases from contestants (one each from Royal Oak, Hopkins, and Wyoming, MI when information provided); handwritten listing of contestants, number of votes received & personae/ costumes (2 cowboy, 1 each of phone lineman, cop, witch doctor, head eater, sailor, convict, druid-alien, & Indian (Native American).
3) Halloween Contest (Oct 30, 1982 date of contest) [Folder 21]
20 completed release forms from contestants, one marked 'Cowboy' (7 Detroit, 2 Warren at the same address, and one each from Flint, Dearborn, Clawson, Birmingham, MI and East Liverpool and Sandusky, OH when information provided), all dated Oct 30, 1982 except two dated Oct 30, 1981 and one changed from 1981 to 1982.
Club Nites at the Outlaw, 1028 W. Seven Mile Rd., Detroit (1981-1982) [Folders 22-23]
1) Hankie Nite Jan 16, 1981
Flyer master with original pen-and-ink drawing, signed JDD 81 (J. Douglas Dennis), showing shirtless male in worn, torn Levis at seat with hanky and keys on the left side (indicating dominant status). Drawing is on the verso of letterhead of J. Frank Dennis, The Farmers Insurance Group, Pontiac, MI.
2) Xmas Celebration, Dec 5, 1981
Flyer master with '350 folded, 50 flat' annotation on verso; 8 Polaroid color photographs showing ASP members/ officers (including Jim Childers, Ernie Horne, Frank Martin, Dan Sivil, Doug Smart, one dressed as Santa Claus in beard, cap & swimsuit, and a bartender(?) in leather chaps et al.) behind the bar and in the interior of the Outlaw.
3) Memorial Day Party/ Uniform-Military Gear, May 29, 1982
Flyer master with original pen-and-ink drawing, signed JDD 82 (J. Douglas Dennis).
Club Nites at the R & R Saloon, 6918 Michigan Ave., Detroit (1982) [Folders 24-25]
1) Raunchy Western Review, Feb 27, 1982
Flyer master with original pen-and-ink drawing, signed JDD 82 (J. Douglas Dennis); 12 black/white snapshots of ASP members/ officers in Western/ leather and drag costumes (including Doug Dennis, Frank Martin, Doug Smart et al.) in the interior of the R & R; card announcement for contest as publicity (slightly larger than a business card).
2) Saugatuck Beach Gear Contest, Jun 19, 1982, alternate date Aug 20, 1982
Flyer master with original pen-and-ink drawing, signed JDD 82 (J. Douglas Dennis), '500 yellow' annotation on verso.
Bar Nite at C.C.W. (Country Western Saloon), 16103 W. Warren, Detroit (Jun 20, 1980) [Folder 26]
Flyer master with original pen-and-ink drawing, signed JDD (J. Douglas Dennis); 'in connection with Lesbian/Gay Pride Celebration'; '200' annotation on verso.
Miscellaneous Materials Related to Club Nites (1981-1982) [Included in Folder 26]
1) Original pen-and-ink drawing for flyer, signed JDD 81 (J. Douglas Dennis) showing a pantless cowboy from the rear in leather chaps.
2) Original master release form for use of photograph and name in print, and request to be added to ASP mailing list ca. 1982.
Series VIII Photographs
1) Envelope marked 'Incoming/ Outgoing Executive Boards- 1982; Newsletter Committee 1981-82; Misc.' [Folder 27]
Contains 19 black/white snapshots in three groups:
1a) 5 photographs of 7 incoming/ outgoing Executive Board members, 1982, see photo marked #5 on verso for seated, left to right: Wes Rogalski, Bill Thompson, Tim Kieselhorst and standing, left to right: ?, Frank Martin, Ernie Horne, ?.
1b) 3 photographs of 5 ASP Newsletter Committee members/ officers, 1981-82, see photo marked #9 on verso for seated, left to right: Jim Childers, Wes Rogalski and standing, left to right: Dan Sivil, Doug Smart and Tim Kieselhorst.
1c) 11 photographs of 4 ASP members/ officers posing in bed together as high jinks, left to right: Ernie Horne, Frank Martin, Bill Thompson, Jim Childers; and 2 ASP officers Dan Sivil & Tim Kieselhorst in bed.
2) One roll of Kodak black/white 35mm safety negative film consisting of 19 shots of the above, 1a-1c. [Included in Folder 27]
3) Envelope marked 'Miscellaneous Photos' ca. 1980's Contains 7 Polaroid color photographs of ASP members/ officers in what appears to be the Woodbridge neighborhood of Midtown Detroit (see street sign for Avery St.) and possibly the interior of the Interchange bar nearby at 1501 Holden (see poster on wall for Selectmen, 10th Anniversary, 198?). Included are: Tim Kieselhorst, Doug Dennis, Frank Martin, others unknown. [Folder 28]
4) Photograph Album with 11 double-sided adhesive pages covered with clear plastic and containing 85 color snapshots & three announcement cards plus 1 loose announcement card in an envelope, documenting the SEMGLA (Southeast Michigan Gay & Lesbian Association, successor to ASP) 'Sixth Annual Raunchy Western Review' on Oct 5, 1985 at the Pink Flamingo bar, 870 W. McNichols, Detroit (formerly Bookie's Club 870/ Gagen's) in Palmer Park. Shown are Ernie Horne, Doug Dennis, Bill Thompson, Frank Martin, & Jim Childers (tuxedo with red bow tie & carnation, also in drag) et al. [Folder 29]
5) Three cut rolls of Kodak color 35mm safety negative film consisting of 93 exposures of the above 85 positives in the Raunchy Western Review Photograph Album and the remainder not represented in the Album; in 3 envelopes each marked 'Childers.' [Folder 30]
Series IX Matchbooks and Matchboxes [Folders 31-32]
Detroit Gay Bars, Restaurants, Baths [Folder 31]
Babyo Club 16890 Telegraph Rd. C.C.A., Southfield, MI 'High Energy Dancing' ca. 1983-84
Back Stage/ Backstage
white cover: Peter Mel's Backstage 1020 W. Seven Mile Rd. 48203 National Press Inc., N. Chicago 'Breakfast Lunch Dinner and After-Theatre Snacks' ca. 1977-1982
black matchbox: Back Stage Diamond Match, New York
Backstreet 15606 Joy Rd. Diamond Match, New York matchbox post 1979
Club Bath Chain (CBC) book of 40 matches 39 American cities, 2 Canadian cities listed with CBC bath houses, including Detroit
Cheeks 13333 W. Eight Mile Rd. 48235 Craig Richard Advertising Specialist Inc., Southfield, MI 'detroit's hottest club' ca. 1982-86
Cove, The 950 W. McNichols Superior Match, Chicago 'Come To The Cove' Serving Breakfast, Lunch and Dinner ca. 1977-1980
Deck, The 14901 E. Jefferson Diamond Match, New York matchbox 'Spirits-Dancing-Entertainment' 'the avant-garde meeting place...where Detroit meets the Pointes.' The reference was to the Grosse Pointes, and also a double entendre for 'phalluses.'
E. Ramp (Entrance Ramp) 19144 Woodward Brown & Bigelow Three-pointed crown & E R with truck cab drawing as a play on Elizabeth Regina/ Queen Elizabeth
Gas Station, The 19106 Woodward Atlantis Match, Chicago 'a man's discotheque and cruise bar'
Glass House, The 950 W. McNichols Rd. Atlantis Match Co., Chicago 'Food & Spirits'
Gold Coast Saloon 2971 E. Seven Mile 48234